Joshua Idahosa

Lagos, Nigeria | idahosajoshua61@gmail.com | +2347065015210 | linkedin.com/in/idahosa-joshua | https://github.com/sazzy-josh

SUMMARY

Highly skilled front-end developer with a focus on creating visually appealing and effective web applications that drive user growth and engagement. Proficient in translating designs into functional code and collaborating with server-side and design teams. Committed to delivering top-quality web experiences for users.

SKILLS

Technical Skills: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Typescript, SCSS, React.Js, Redux, Vue, Vuex, Vuetify, Pinia, GraphQL, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, Firebase, Docker, Git And Github, Framer Motion

EXPERIENCE

Frontend Engineer(Full-time)

Bento Africa

Jan 2023 - Present

- Perform code reviews to encourage quality, reusable, and more efficient code.
- Implement Figma designs into code, ensuring accuracy and adherence to design specifications with Vuetify and Nuxt.
- . Contributed to the design and development of the company's most recent products versions, pay v3, which resulted in improved engagement with customers.

Frontend Developer (Remote)

Proprein Labs

June 2022 - Dec 2022, Lagos, Nigeria

- Developed unique user interfaces that increased user interaction and user experience by 20% with React and Redux.
- Optimized components for maximum performance across a vast array of web-capable devices and browsers.
- Performed unit Testing with RTL and Jest to ensure quality and scalable products.
- · Synchronized with the development team to ideate on possible UI ideas and implementation.
- Fixed bugs and solved problems detected through testing.

Frontend Developer (Contractor)

Class 54 Education

March 2022 - May 2022, Remote

- $\cdot \ Translated \ Figma \ designs \ and \ prototypes \ into \ pixel-perfect \ user \ interfaces.$
- Built reusable components and libraries with Vue.js for future use.
- Implemented a chart feature that visualizes students' performance with chart.js.
- · Liaised with external teams to develop specifications for applications while ensuring quality deliveries.

Frontend Intern

ZeroToMastery Academy

September 2021 - April 2022, Remote

- · Developed front-end codes in a timely and high-quality manner while ensuring a consistent look and feel.
- Succeeded in creating react web applications that automated a time consuming business process thereby generating more revenue.
- Collaborated with other team members on the development team.
- Incorporated redux to handle effective state management and dynamic nature of the web application.

PROJECTS

Chicken City | Github Repo

A food delivery E-commerce web application built with React.js, Tailwind CSS, Redux, Flutterwave SDK as payment gateway, and firebase as its backend intended to allow users make orders anywhere within Nigeria and get it delivered at the comfort of their home.

- · Implemented user login/signup functionality and Google authentication with Firebase.
- · Created an interactive and animated sidebar on small screens (mobile view) with Framer motion.
- •Implementation of Protected routes to grant only authenticated users access to some specific routes.
- •Integrated a secured payment checkout through Pay with bank transfer, USSD, and card payment with Flutterwave SDK.

Foodie | Github Repo

A single-page web application, built with React.js utilizing React query and React slick, provides users with the ability to search for and explore a wide range of recipes from different culinary traditions. It allows users to filter their search results, save their favorite recipes, and view detailed information about each recipe.

- Implemented a search feature to enable its users to search for varieties of recipes.
- Experience with Rest APIs to fetch data.
- Used local storage to store and retrieve insensitive user data during the transition between different pages.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

<u>HertechTrail</u>(Web Development Coach)

Jan 2023 - Present

- · Offering mentorship to over 50 young women interested in pursuing careers in tech.
- Create learning materials and resources, including lectures, exercises, and project briefs, to support the students in their learning journey.

EDUCATION

Bachelor Of Science (Computer Science)

University Of Benin · Edo State, Nigeria · 2021

COURSEWORK

Front-end Development with React

The Hong Kong University Of Science and Technology • 2022.

HTML,CSS and Javascript for Web Developers

John Hopkins University • 2022

Responsive Web Design

Freecodecamp.org • 2022

Front-End Web UI Frameworks and Tools: Bootstrap 4

Coursera · 2022

NA.		